ADAM MOHAMMED

04 Moorgate Leadenhall, Milton Keynes, MK65NA · 07448584934 adamekissa@gmail.com

I am excited about the field of software lifecycle I and would appreciate the opportunity to bring my experience and creativity to your growing team. I have excellent communication and servant leadership skills. I have a strong understanding of technical processes within software development and lifecycle. I stay up-to-speed with innovative technologies and test the promising ones to make sure I do not miss game-changing opportunities to boost productivity and stay relevant.

EXPERIENCE

JANUARY 2020 – OCTOBER 2021 SOFTWARE TESTER/ DEVELOPER (FREELANCE)

Some of my key roles in testing were to test user experience and draft extensive report on any bugs met.

I regularly conducted integration and deployment tests using platforms like GitHub and Netlify. Also, unit tests of application functions and core logic using jest, supertest and typescript when needed.

I helped teams in designing, developing, and working with Restful API using node.js and Express.

I collaborated through agile development, regular code reviews and commits, and other less formal communication.

I also have experience in building React applications using frameworks like Next and Gatsby.

I have experience working with PHP frameworks like Laravel, WordPress plugins, and customization of WordPress templates.

I have a valuable experience working with React, JavaScript, ES6 and TypeScript.

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2021

MOBILE SOLUTION AGENT, VODAFONE

I Served as the first contact with customers for complaint logging and feedbacks on products and services and cross selling new products and services.

I worked closely with cross functional teams to ensure we meet the set sprint goals.

I Initiates reversals on wrong and duplicate transactions reported by customers and systems.

I undertook verification of customer's identity using various KYC methods on request.

I led the coding club through my time at Vodafone Ghana where we did peer learning of useful programing languages and concepts. The code club went ahead to flag many bugs in some of the applications we were using inhouse to improve them.

NOVEMBER 2017 – FEBRUARY 2018 SCRUM MASTER, AKADITI

I tracked the Progress report and sprint metrics using scrum boards and Kanban.

organized scrum events.

I Worked with the teams to show its ability to ensure we meet the sprint aims.

I also worked with the team on various Continuous Delivery pipelines with automated quality gates.

I worked with the team on successful DevOps focused delivery pipeline projects.

I had active participation in the maturation process of the Agile model and methodologies within the organization.

With the help of agile tools like Trello and Kanban board, I ensured teams are practicing the core agile principles of collaboration, prioritization, team accountability, and made visible progress and roadmap using various metrics.

AUGUST 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

WEB DEVELOPER, AKADITI

I regularly check and improve the quality of our products by bugs fixing and refactoring code base, where necessary.

I actively took part in designing and building bespoke web application for the organization.

I wrote scalable and high-quality code.

I regularly updated and test existing app functionalities

Conducting of SEO for various applications and services.

EDUCATION

OCTOBER 2021 - APRIL 2022

SCHOOL OF CODE – ENGLAND, UNITED KINGDOM

This is an Intensive Full-Stack Development bootcamp covering areas ranging from JS and React to NodeJS, Databases, TDD, Agile Methodology and Cloud.

MARCH 2017

AITI-KACE () DIPLOMA IN BUSINESS COMPUTING

I designed and built a web-based courier service management system for my final year project.

MAY 2013

BSC HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT, ZENITH UNIVERSITY COLLEGE

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML and CSS
- Node is
- PHP Laravel
- Scrum Master with certification by Scrum.org
- Teamwork
- Jest and supertest

- REACT
- Typescript
- Unit and integration testing
- Agile Methodology
- Express
- Next and Gatsby
- Restful API

- GitHub
- SQL
- C# and .NET Framework

- Trello, Jira, and slack
- Continuous integration and Continuous deployment

ACTIVITIES

VOLUNTEER

Techiman Zongo Community ICT training, Techiman, Ghana.

I taught over 300 hours (about 2 weeks) of HTML and CSS in the community ICT classes between JULY 2016 and NOVEMBER 2016.

LINKEDIN PROFILE

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-mohammed-16457512a GITHUN PROFILE adamekissa (github.com)

REFERENCE available on demand